Welcome to the...conference I am...other degree I'm a principle
develop on the visual cplus-plus team in visual studio I'm here today
to talk about optimizing your...
Using visual studio cpluscplus-plus two thousand fifteen.
So, let's talk about too brigade sone is
let's talk about developer productivity for cplus...projects...to relates to
...times and then we'll go...some of the features we have in
visual studio two thousand fifteen to speed up the ...
So,...productivity ski as a developer...go
...the edit build and debug cycles multiple times a day and the
...during these cycles
is pretty significant for cplus-plus projects and a key goal for us during
vision studio two thousand fifteen was to try to reduce this...
tax in the cycle so that developers of...and you can
...large developer gains across...teams so let's go and
talk about some of the features we have for visual studio
twenty fifty the...feature I want to talk about is incremental link there's a
feature that's been there for quite a few versions in visual studio.
we have made some expert enhancements to this feature did they were.
We analyzed the failures using telemetry
data and we notice that we're missing a few...cases which we have gone and,
fixed so that when you hit...makes changes that could these
...cases you don't need to do a full-length you can get increment link.
The largest costs the largest failure was due to static
Large projects typically have.
Multiple static clips that they...and then the very
the binary using the static lips as a part of daily activity when the data but
...touches a static lip we would give up on incremental
...can go to...link.
And, the difference between us incremental lincoln full-length for these projects
with quite significant we saw some projects that take for minutes the link for
full-length what incremental link was thirty seconds so if you
...static lab although the change that you may to the
statically would not require full-length just because you're change the statically we
...we just gave up on...linking so we have
fixed stack so if you make any changes to a static
lab we can now try to do incremental link and we have
seen quite a few internal games projects
that are now linking in thirty seconds whereas...that...for
...more to link so that's incremental link enhancements
...existing features the next one is template processing.
With modern code the use of templates has
increased quite a...and we expect that in the future that's going to increase
significantly and as we are working through conformance features for templates
no compiler we also looked at how we process template code and
made significant changes in the way we deal with that.
As a result of all of these changes we see some.
...big speedup...template crossing based on the
project size and the contents of the projects we...seen anywhere from.
Fifty percent speedup to ten-x speedup in those extreme cases where
...source file has a lot of templates.
The third feature is
...processing pbs.
Contain debug information and.
For any good debugging experience in need to have the pb available
And, up-to-date so that you get your if you are productive during the debugging,
debugging
experience what we noticed as we analyzed are build systems.
Build cycles where
pb processing took some significant time both during compiling link.
And, we the...caught...cost the reasons for this
slow down and we have fix those issues so all these the first three.
Features I'm talking about you get automatically as soon as upgrade...to
...fifteen.
...project is already using incremental link you should see some speedup you...of template
...code automatically you should see some speedup data as well and
pb processing is across-the-board the next for features
are features that are new to visions
...thousand fifteen and you have to change...project settings to make use
of them the first one is still related to pbs something that we
...debug fast link.
The way let's talk a little bit about how we generate
...pbs when the compiler
...coded generates a pb which we call the compiler generated
...are if you use the z seven switch it puts the debug information into the
object files and then we link all of these object files
...linking is happening the link color is
...extracting all the debug information that.
Is required for the final binary and putting into a lincoln...
When we analyzed the time that...spend?
Processing pbs.
During linking it was all related to extracting this information from
this various sources and putting into one five for large projects that can be quite a bit of
data we have seen games with more than one gigabyte
pb files.
And, all that takes quite a bit process.
So, we came up with this new feature that.
Allows you to speedup links significantly
without affecting your debug experience with so the change here is that when
link-up starts and you have this...new specified new switch specified the
...keeps the debug information in the compiler generated
...object files it then generates a pb that has links to these.
Pbs and object files
and then puts and information that only it can generate
so the pb processing is now significantly split up in some
ling curve situated some linking situations we have seen...we take up to fifty percent of the link
time and for those projects it's now the pb
crossing is very small it's more it's more like five percent of the...
time so you get some significant speedup and then when the neighbor?
When you start your debugging sections session debug are knows that this is a different type of
...it can go get the by information from the?
Location where that.
Is available at either the compiler generated...the
...js and then ...give
you all the debug information you don't have any loss of fidelity during debugging neither
...data any performance impact in the debug?
So, that's the first feature that you can use by changing
...project settings the next one
is the switch to the compiler called cc knowing line.
...results in the compiler generating fewer symbols and
essentially than the link are has less to deal with and can speedup
ling significantly so, what happens when this switch
is any function that's mongers inline but not reference
in the compilation unique is?
Essentially there's no code generated for it
and it's as if the code wasn't present as a result we have seen that static lipton
...days are about thirty percent smaller.
And, the speedup we get from.
The in the...is due to reasons less io because of the smaller size
...js and then our static lips and
...is...because it doesn't need to deal with all of the symbols that are not referenced
and then hand doesn't need to worry about throwing those symbols of
it so that's a speedup that you can see with the switch.
There is a potential for breaking some of exist some of the existing
sources as a result of using the switch but using the switch gives you more conformance
code and fixing the issues is trivial we have some
...talk about how to address these on...I'll talk about the location of...cyclical.
The next feature is ling time-code generation...generation has been there for multiple
versions and some people user and complain about the
...times other people have stopped using it because of the productivity,
productivity hit in the...we added a new.
New feature here which we call this fast...time-code
...and the idea here being on the first.
Optimize...says of a information about the analysis
...perform as well as the cody generated into a database
...next varied after your made some changes...code.
When you start the...the?
Compiler and figure out the
...the database from previous big.
Picks up all information from there doesn't analysis to figure out the delta of
what needs to be regenerated it regenerate score only for the
...only for the parts of the binding that are impacted gets the
rest of the code from the database queries the database for all information from the previous
built and then generates the binary
then result is a binary that has the same.
Optimization level...the as a binary that your created if you
...clean...and the binary is also a
...binary that is a does not have any artifacts in
it that would sort of more debug information on some...additional
...in the in this binary or any such artifacts are not present in the
...so it is achievable binary we have been using this
feature internally from the time it's come online for about six
to nine months.
And, we see about
for x improvement in our base times because we use link
time-code generation on our binary and every developer when...typically they use the
ling time-code generation to build the binary is a
for x improvement in for most of the changes that we make is a significant developer
So, the new fast
...time-code...switch not only now allows you to get the performance gain
...application also but also brings the productivity in this area the
last topic I want to talk about is an extension to the id to analyze
...so pc...is a mechanism by which we can speedup
compile times this mechanism is used
by different compilers not just visual studio and.
Vc significant speedup in break times as a result of using
...one of the things we noticed was that pc h go up
...very quickly as changes are made to
the project new headers are required to build
a project and typically those header don't end up in the pc
h that could
when it's quite possible to put them there so this extension is
...first step and sort of analyzing your code during design-time and start giving
you hints about making changes steer code to improve...times.
Yes, there are other analysis tools that give you...details about your code
of how to improve your code but this one is the first-time we are trying to do
something that can help analyzer project to speed up your
...so the way to use this is go to the visual studio gallery
the search for the...it analysis extension and then download and install
it once you have it there.
You should start getting hints about changes you can make
the pc h to speed up your break times currently the
...only this...only analysis
...to pc edge for files that could be included in it but I can definitely
for see us making enhancements to also detect cases where
...file that should not be included in the pc it is into
...are files that are only required for a certain configuration
end up in a defy in if deaf blog that can be used only for the
configuration and not have to slowdown other configurations so these are some of
the great features some of these features...get for free as soon as you up a
great to visual studio two thousand fifteen others you had to make some changes to
...projects to get those features we are updating are
visual studio templates to sort of give you the best very time for
that configuration but if you have for the existing projects you have to go and apply some of these manually.
Let's talk a little bit about future.
Yes, we have done some analysis right now we have split up a few things but what
are the key things that we think in the future are going to help with speeding up the
...for cplus-plus projects the first one is the cplus-plus
modules proposal that the cplus...standards committee is
looking at right now this proposal has multipleadvantages
one of them that I'm going to focus on here is the potential for this.
Modules featured to speed abate times today when you include
...header file we had to transit daily include all the...files
that are required in every compilation unit...it
helps with that a little bit but you have to into all of them even for types that
are internal implementation details of a...let's say you
need to include headers that satisfied that types so.
...the cplus-plus...model is requires us to include
...more head of the necessary modules can help us because
it's encapsulates helps us encapsulate implementation details
away from the enduser in a much better way we think it
also has now the potential of speeding of base significantly and
...multiplecompiler windows are looking at this feature and they're
also discussing this actively in
cplus-plus standards committee so that's one of the features that we think
will make a big impact the other thing that we notice was.
The build analysis tools.
We have tools to do
static analysis but we don't have many tools to help you figure out
...time spent a number of changes that can make to
...project improbable...analysis...first step we expect to add more
he in this area to help you find those bottlenecks and start addressing them.
So, in basically visual studio two
thousand fifteen gives you a lot of these features and...
Fasting out says gold download two thousand fifteen install it
tryout these features some of them we get for free others you have to make changes to
For a lot of this information we have blog posts.
For some of these features already on our blog psych either features we're going to
talk about and future blocks so definitely visit the vc...
Site to get more information about these features and as well as other features that we have
...studio two thousand fifteen.
So, thanks for listening to my talk and
...you have faster belts using visual studio two thousand fifty.